# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello everyone, this is Wang Gang
# 本期视频我跟大家分享一道小吃
In today's video, I'll share the recipe of a snack
# 首先我们准备花生米500克放入盆中
First, prepare 500g of peanuts in a pot
# 加入适量的清水浸泡60分钟备用
Add some water and soak them for 60 minutes
# 浸泡的目的是为了更好地搓掉花生皮
This makes removing the skin easier later
# 喜欢吃皮的同学也可以不用搓
You can also leave the skin there if you like
# 但是必须浸泡
But soaking in water is a must
# 然后将去皮的花生米再次淘洗干净备用
Then rinse the peanuts with their skin removed and set them aside
# 同学们如果是新鲜的花生米也可以直接制作
If the peanuts are fresh, you can ignore these previous steps
# 下一步开始配制辅料
Next, prepare other ingredients
# 碗中加入八角2颗
Add 2 pieces of star anises to the bowl
# 加入桂皮2小块
Add 2 small pieces of cinnamon
# 然后准备适量的子弹头剪成辣椒丝备用
Then prepare some "Zidantou" chili peppers and cut them into slices
# 喜欢吃更辣的同学可以换成小米干辣椒
If you can eat very spicy food, you can use Xiaomi dried chili peppers instead
# 再加入适量的青花椒
Then add some green Sichuan peppercorns
# 不喜欢吃麻的同学也可以不加
If you don't want the peanuts to be numbing, don't add them
# 再加入适量的高度白酒浸泡20分钟备用
Then add some hard liquor baijiu and soak for 20 minutes
# 白酒浸泡的目的是“榨”出辣味和麻味
This is to enhance the spicy and numbing flavors
# 同学们白酒也可以反复使用降低成本
You can reuse baijiu to lower the cost
# 下一步开始制作
Next, start cooking
# 首先我们在锅中加入适量的清水
First we add some water to the wok
# 然后加入剥好皮的花生米
Then add the pealed peanuts
# 大火烧开之后转小火煮五分钟将其煮熟
After it boils, turn to low heat and boil for 5 minutes
# 中途可以加入适量的白醋
You can add some rice vinegar midway
# 加白醋可以让花生米的颜色更白更纯
Adding rice vinegar can make the peanuts' color purely white
# 5分钟之后捞出放入冰箱中冰冻30分钟冷却
After 5 minutes, remove the peanuts from water and put them in the freezer for 30 minutes
# 花生米经过一冷一热之后会变得更脆
Peanuts become more crunchy after the quick change of temperature
# 30分钟之后取出花生米开始制作
After 30 minutes, take out the peanuts and start cooking
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First we heat up the wok
# 锅烧热之后加入小宽油
When the wok is heated, add some Kuan You
# 然后直接下入冻好的花生米
Then add the frozen peanuts
# 开中小火炸制五分钟左右
Use medium-low heat to fry for around 5 minutes
# 将其炸脆
Until they become crunchy
# 家庭小灶则需要8分钟左右
If you cook at home, it takes around 8 minutes
# 花生米炸脆之后捞出备用
Take the peanuts out after they become crunchy
# 下一步开始炒制
Then start stir-frying
# 锅中加入少许的底油烧至五成热
Add some base oil and heat it to around 150 degrees celsius
# 然后加入处理好的花椒辣椒小火爆香
Then add pre-processed peppercorns and chili peppers and bring out the aroma with low heat
# 辣椒爆香之后下入炸好的花生米小火翻炒10分钟左右
After you smell the peppers, add the fried peanuts and stir-fry for 10 minutes
# 同学们花椒辣椒经过浸泡所以不怕炒糊
Since we've soaked the peppercorns and chili peppers in water, they won't be burnt
# 中途加入适量的食用盐和白糖调味
Add some salt and sugar midway
# 其中盐可以是平时炒菜的三倍
You can add three times as much salt as you usually do when cooking
# 否则不够咸
Or it won't be salty enough
# 起锅之前再加入少许的高度白酒翻炒一分钟即可
Before we're done, add a little bit of baijiu and stir-fry for another minute
# 加白酒的目的是增香
This is to enhance the flavors
# 也可以让花生米长时间保持脆度
and let the peanuts stay crunchy for a long time
# 翻炒一分钟之后将花生米倒出放凉即可食用
After one minute, pour our the peanuts and let them cool down before we eat
# 一道非常香辣爽脆的下酒花生米就制作完成
A very tasty, spicy, and crunchy peanuts that go well with wine is finished
# 下面开始技术总结
Now let's summarize the techniques
# 第一
First
# 花生米最好选择陈花生米
When choosing peanuts, older ones are better
# 这样经过浸泡之后很容易将皮搓掉
Because their skin is easier to remove after soaking
# 第二
Secondly
# 花生米经过一冷一热再油炸可以变得异常酥脆
Freezing the peanuts and then frying it can make it extra crunchy
# 第三
Thirdly
# 不喜欢麻辣的同学也可以用其他香料代替花椒辣椒
If you don't like the spicy and numbing flavor, you can replace peppercorns and peppers with other spices
# 麻辣花生米的技术总结完毕
Above is all techniques for Spicy and Numbing Peanuts